Welcome to the Large Volume
Parental Preparation
Demonstration Lab.
Video hand hygiene and garbing
procedures have been performed.
Calculations and pharmacist
verification have been
performed.
All supply items have been
cleaned with 70% sterile
isopropyl alcohol prior to
placing in the outer 6 inches of
the primary engineering control.
You'll take off the outer
packaging of the ID bag and
place the bag on the direct
compounding area and throw the
outer wrapper.
You're going to clean with
sterile IPA before returning
into the hood.
We can hang that bag on a hook
of the hang bar and set over to
the left.
The supply items are placed on
the DCA to help you learn the
order of the large volume
parental manipulation.
We have our potassium chloride
stock vial, our sterile IPA
swabs, our syringe, our regular
needle.
We'll open that sterile IPA swab
and we'll place it on the DCA.
We'll take the cap off of our
vial.
We'll open a second sterile IPA
swab.
Pay attention to that horizontal
air flow and that side of the
prep pad.
We're going to clean the septum
of our vial and we're going to
peel back the outer packaging of
our syringe.
We want to hold on to those
flaps so they don't interfere
with the air flow from the HEPA
filter.
We're going to remove the
syringe, making sure that that
syringe tip stays in the air
flow.
We'll peel back the packaging of
our needle.
We'll attach the needle to the
syringe.
We'll recheck our connection.
We'll activate the syringe so
that we loosen that plunger.
We'll pull the flat knob back to
the volume that we need for our
patient dose.
We will get into a dark
position.
We want to take the cap off and
we'll put it on that sterile IPA
swab.
You want to be bevel up.
You'll tippy toe to 12:00, and
6:00 will invert the vial by the
barrel.
You'll pull the syringe so that
the needle is in liquid.
We'll begin the milking method.
We have the forefinger and
middle finger that are on the
flaps of the syringe.
The thumb will push against the
flat knob, and as you milk,
you'll be able to feel that
pressure.
The syringe will equilibrate.
We're going to troubleshoot any
bubbles that are in our syringe
by the barrel.
We're going to push that needle
into our vial, and this time we
are going to use the work
surface to clear that bubble.
Then we'll bring the needle tip
back into liquid and we'll
resume the milking method to get
rid of all of the air that is in
the syringe.
And we want to make sure that
there's no bubbles from the tip
of that needle.
We need the hub and lumen full
of fluid.
We'll change our hand position.
We'll pull to the volume of our
patient dose.
And then we'll turn the wheel to
8:00 and 2:00.
We'll come out of the vial.
We'll replace the cap.
You'll tap, slide and snap.
We will get a pharmacist check.
You can put your finger behind
the graduation marks to ensure
that we have the volume that we
need for our patient and then
we'll slide our bag over.
This alligated port has a tubing
port that is long and in our
way.
We can turn that bag around and
now we have better access to our
our port.
We're going to open a sterile
IPA swab, and we're going to
clean that injection port of the
bag.
Notice that it curls toward the
HEPA filter, but it's still
getting beautiful air flow.
Now we want to be overhand.
We'll take our cap off our
syringe and we'll hold on to the
injection port on our bag.
And you want to go straight into
the bag.
We don't need to worry about the
bevel on our needle.
Just go straight into the bag
and with your thumb you're going
to push the liquid into the bag
and then youire going to hold on
to the barrel and pull straight
out of the bag.